<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://samuel-huron.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://samuel-huron.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-11-28T13:03:27+00:00</updated><id>https://samuel-huron.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Habiliation à Diriger Des Recherche - Presentation</title><link href="https://samuel-huron.github.io/blog/2025/HDR-samuel-huron-supplemental/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Habiliation à Diriger Des Recherche - Presentation"/><published>2025-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://samuel-huron.github.io/blog/2025/HDR-samuel-huron-supplemental</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://samuel-huron.github.io/blog/2025/HDR-samuel-huron-supplemental/"><![CDATA[<p>It is my great pleasure to invite you to my public presentation for the Habilitation à diriger des recherches (HDR). It will take place in English (with a strong frencg accent) on 3 December at 2 p.m. at Télécom Paris (the lecture room will be the Amphi Thevenin, or if it’s change it will be posted at the reception desk) and on <a href="https://telecom-paris.zoom.us/j/98092512156?pwd=AfyrTyn7BMaDc1VPPo6FyNxyUL7W5b.1">Zoom</a>.</p> <p>Please register here if you wish to attend physically: <a href="https://evento.renater.fr/survey/samuel-huron-hdr-05ssscsq">https://evento.renater.fr/survey/samuel-huron-hdr-05ssscsq</a></p> <h2 id="jury">Jury</h2> <p>The jury will be composed of:</p> <ul> <li>Céline Coutrix, CNRS Researcher, University of Grenoble Alpes.</li> <li>Annie Gentes, Professor, Director of Research, CY School of Design</li> <li>Lucy Kimbell, Professor of Contemporary Design Practices, Central Saint Martins,</li> <li>Wendy Elizabeth Mackay, Research Director, INRIA, University of Paris Saclay</li> <li>Miriah Meyer, Professor, Linköpings Universitet</li> </ul> <h2 id="abstract">Abstract</h2> <p>The manuscript is entitled ``<strong>Data Representation, Output to Input</strong>’’.</p> <p>I have spent the last ten years exploring how humans can construct data representations that are accessible to all and low-cost, using various means such as sketching on paper or building with physical tokens. I compared these to digital tools and reflected on how they differ and complement each other. I then became interested in how experts from different fields (art, design, research) construct and produce physical representations of data. Finally, I studied with my doctoral students the use of data representations in the fields of energy feedback devices and online debate platforms.</p> <p>These diverse works led me to question the relationship between data and its representations in the digital world.</p> <p>With the tools mentioned above, humans produce data by creating their own representations and adding data to them. However, in the community of visualisation and human-machine interactions, for the past 20 or 30 years, there has been a clear distinction between visualisations intended to represent <em>existing</em> data and graphical interfaces that allow data to be captured, manipulated, and represented.</p> <p>My co-authors and I explored this dilemma within a design space that allowed us to define and show how data visualisations can also be a means of collecting and modifying data for various purposes, such as: individual reflection, public collective reflection, documentation of public activities, discussion of data, investigation, planning, and collective organisation. This new paradigm for visualisations opens up a vast, underexplored field of research.</p> <p>To conclude this presentation, I will attempt to offer a practical and critical reflection on the different methods I have used over the past ten years: qualitative visual data analysis and design spaces. Finally, if I have time, I would like to offer a provocative question: why, over the last 30 years, has the field of data visualisation given little or no consideration to the issue of input in data visualisations?</p> <h2 id="references">References</h2> <p>This habilitation is based on the following work</p> <p>Micro focus on Designing and Authoring Visualization :</p> <ul> <li>Jagoda Walny, Samuel Huron, and Sheelagh Carpendale. <strong>An exploratory study of data sketching for visual representation.</strong> In <em>Computer Graphics Forum</em>, volume 34, pages 231–240. Wiley Online Library, 2015. doi: https://doi.org/10.1111/cgf.12635 <ul> <li><a href="http://sheelaghcarpendale.ca/innovis/uploads/Publications/Publications/Walny2014_DataSketches.pdf">Paper</a></li> <li><a href="https://supplemental-material.github.io/Data-Sketching/">Supplemental material</a></li> <li><a href="https://fr.slideshare.net/slideshow/an-exploratory-study-of-data-sketching-for-visual-representation-eurovis-2015/48787350">Presentation deck</a></li> </ul> </li> <li>Alice Thudt, Uta Hinrichs, Samuel Huron, and Sheelagh Carpendale. <strong>Self-reflection and personal physicalization construction</strong>. <em>Proceedings of the CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</em>, CHI’ 18, page 1–13, New York, NY, USA, 2018. Association for Computing Machinery. doi: https://doi.org/10.1145/3173574.3173728. <ul> <li><a href="https://inria.hal.science/hal-02310547/">Paper</a></li> <li><a href="">Supplemental material</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9Cho8jvlDFY">Full presentation</a></li> </ul> </li> <li>Tiffany Wun, Jennifer Payne, Samuel Huron, and Sheelagh Carpendale. <strong>Comparison of bar chart authoring with Microsoft Excel and tangible tiles</strong>. <em>In Computer Graphics Forum</em>, volume 35, pages 111–120. Wiley Online Library, 2016. doi: https://doi.org/10.1111/cgf.12887. <ul> <li><a href="https://hal.science/hal-01400906/">Paper</a></li> <li><a href="https://supplemental-material.github.io/Comparing-excel-tiles/">Supplemental material</a></li> </ul> </li> <li>Wei Wei, Samuel Huron, and Yvonne Jansen. <strong>Towards autocomplete strategies for visualization construction</strong>. In <em>2023 IEEE Visualization and Visual Analytics (VIS)</em>, pages 141–145, 2023. doi: 10.1109/VIS54172.2023.00037. <ul> <li><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2308.02679">Paper</a></li> <li><a href="https://osf.io/nu4z3/overview">Supplemental material on OSF</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cxwSHXvzSSQ">Full presentation</a></li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p>Meso focus on physicalization :</p> <ul> <li>Sandra Bae, Clement Zheng, Mary Etta West, Ellen Yi-Luen Do, Samuel Huron, and Danielle Albers Szafir. 2022. <strong>Making Data Tangible: A Cross-disciplinary Design Space for Data Physicalization</strong>. In <em>Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI ‘22)</em>. Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, Article 81, 1–18. https://doi.org/10.1145/3491102.3501939 <ul> <li><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2202.10520">Paper</a> * <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mj1Oveo5_u0&amp;t=3s">Video</a></li> <li><a href="https://inputvisualization.github.io/">Compagnon website</a></li> <li>Page on <a href="https://sandrabae.github.io/dataphys-gallery/index.html">Sandra website</a></li> </ul> </li> <li>Samuel Huron, Till Nagel, Lora Oehlberg, and Wesley Willett, eds. <strong>Making with data: Physical design and craft in a data-driven world</strong>. <em>A K Peters/CRC Press</em>, 2022. https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003264903 <ul> <li><a href="[https://makingwithdata.org/](https://www.taylorfrancis.com/books/edit/10.1201/9781003264903/making-data-samuel-huron-till-nagel-lora-oehlberg-wesley-willett)">Order the book</a></li> <li><a href="https://makingwithdata.org/">Making with data: Physical design and craft in a data-driven world</a></li> <li><a href="https://makingwithdata.org/2023-in-review/">Video to present the book</a></li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p>Meso focus on debates platforms and :</p> <ul> <li>Tallullah Frappier, Nathalie Bressa, and Samuel Huron. 2024. <strong>Jumping to Conclusions: A Visual Comparative Analysis of Online Debate Platform Layouts</strong>. In <em>Proceedings of the 13th Nordic Conference on Human-Computer Interaction (NordiCHI ‘24)</em>. Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, Article 42, 1–15. https://doi.org/10.1145/3679318.3685377 <ul> <li><a href="https://hal-ciheam.iamm.fr/INFOLOGY-INFOLOGIE/hal-04784834v1">Paper</a></li> <li><a href="https://osf.io/kz32y/">Supplemental material</a></li> </ul> </li> <li>Samuel Lacroix, Thesis, <strong>Domesticating the energy information. : Comparing the feedback device design choices and user practices to develop a new design approach</strong>, 28/05/2020. Institut polytechnique de Paris <ul> <li><a href="https://theses.fr/2020IPPAT014">Thesis of Samuel Lacroix- in french </a></li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p>Macro focus on debates platforms and :</p> <ul> <li>Nathalie Bressa, Jordan Louis, Wesley Willett, and Samuel Huron. <strong>Input visualization: Collecting and modifying data with visual representations</strong> . In <em>Proceedings of the CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</em>, CHI ’24, pages 1–18, New York, USA, 2024. Association for Computing Machinery. doi: https://doi.org/10.1145/3613904.3642808. <ul> <li><a href="https://imt.hal.science/hal-04558867v1/file/InputVisualization-CHI2024-AuthorVersion.pdf">Paper</a></li> <li><a href="https://osf.io/bw3gp/">Supplemental material</a></li> <li><a href="https://inputvisualization.github.io/">Compagnon website</a></li> <li><a href="https://inputvisualization.github.io/vis2025/">Workshop at VIS 2025</a></li> <li><a href="https://osf.io/bw3gp/files/7jbp9">Presentation in pdf of the Examples</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RAfv2quE6nA">Presentation in video by Nathalie</a></li> </ul> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="HDR"/><category term="Habilitation"/><category term="recherche"/><category term="design"/><category term="social"/><category term="sciences"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Habiliation a diriger des recherche - Presentation]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recrutement d’ingénieur d’étude</title><link href="https://samuel-huron.github.io/blog/2025/recrutement-ingenieur-recherche/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recrutement d’ingénieur d’étude"/><published>2025-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://samuel-huron.github.io/blog/2025/recrutement-ingenieur-recherche</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://samuel-huron.github.io/blog/2025/recrutement-ingenieur-recherche/"><![CDATA[<p>Pour candidater passer par le plateforme CNRS entre le 10 juin et 10 Juillet : <a href="https://carrieres.cnrs.fr/concours-externes-des-ingenieurs-et-techniciens-h-f/">https://carrieres.cnrs.fr/concours-externes-des-ingenieurs-et-techniciens-h-f/</a></p> <h2 id="mission">Mission</h2> <p>La mission comprend la conception d’outils de recueil de données qualitatives et quantitatives (méthode mixte), plus particulièrement de données audio, vidéo et numériques, ainsi que le traitement de ces données. L’ingénieur-e d’études recruté-e pilotera des dispositifs de collecte, de traitement et d’étude de données. Il-elle garantira et validera la qualité des données produites et des traitements réalisés.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="activités">Activités</h2> <p>L’ingénieur-e d’études interviendra dans le cadre du déploiement de grands équipements de recherche pour la collecte et l’analyse de données d’interaction : l’Observation Lab (plateforme de captation de données comportementales et studio mobile d’enregistrement d’activités), le Studio Design (espace de création low- et mid-tech) et le Hyve-3D (système de conception et de visualisation immersif).</p> <p>Il-elle devra :</p> <ul> <li>Contribuer à la définition et mise en œuvre des protocoles méthodologiques permettant leur utilisation (montage vidéo, gestion des données, gestion des modèles 3D, etc).</li> <li>Contribuer au traitement des données collectées</li> <li>Assurer la maintenance, la gestion des fournitures et la logistique de réservation de ces équipements.</li> <li>Fournir un appui aux chercheur·euse·s, et étudiant·e·s notamment dans le cadre des expérimentations scientifiques en lien avec ces outils : définition de plans d’expérience, rédaction des communications scientifiques…</li> <li>Participer à la conception et à la mise en œuvre d’activités d’enseignement utilisant ces équipements, en collaboration avec les chercheur·euse·s et doctorants de l’équipe La personne recrutée pourra être amenée à se déplacer ponctuellement sur des terrains, en France ou à l’international.</li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="compétences">Compétences</h2> <ul> <li>Méthode de collecte et d’analyse de données audio vidéo, physiologiques (eye tracking et autres).</li> <li>Connaissance de plusieurs méthodes d’analyse qualitative et quantitative parmi les suivantes: grounded theory; analyse thématique; codage ouvert; codage axial; analyses factorielles ; analyse de corrélations uni et multivariées ; classification ; régression ; études randomisées contrôlées; techniques de datamining; traitement automatique des langues.</li> <li>Connaissances générales des cadres juridiques relatifs au traitement de données en SHS</li> </ul> <p>Compétences opérationnelles:</p> <ul> <li>Maitriser les opérations de prétraitement de données : mise en forme des données, contrôle de la validité et de la qualité, traitement des données manquantes, transformation des variables.</li> <li>Savoir gérer les flux vidéos et audio multi canaux, sous la diversité des formats vidéo et des protocoles d’encodage</li> <li>Maitrise d’un ou plusieurs outils d’édition vidéos et audios</li> <li>Maitrise des langages R, Python et SQL</li> <li>Savoir rédiger des présentations écrites et orales (rédaction de rapport, participation à l’écriture d’article de recherche)</li> <li>Maitriser la suite Office.</li> <li>Langue anglaise : être capable de lire, comprendre et écrire en anglais. Niveau B2 (cadre européen commun de référence pour les langues).</li> </ul> <p>Compétences comportementales :</p> <ul> <li>Travail en équipe (notamment avec les chercheurs impliqués lors de l’interprétation des données),</li> <li>Curiosité intellectuelle (être capable d’appréhender des objets de recherche variés)</li> <li>Sens critique</li> <li>Autonomie.</li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="contexte">Contexte</h2> <p>L’institut Interdisciplinaire de l’Innovation est une unité mixte de recherche (UMR 9217), qui regroupe plus de 225 personnes, dont environ 80 chercheur·euse·s et 120 doctorant·e·s répartis sur 3 sites : École polytechnique, Télécom Paris et Mines Paris PSL. Il étudie de manière interdisciplinaire (essentiellement économie, gestion et sociologie) les phénomènes d’innovation dans leurs dimensions multiples (technologique, sociétale et organisationnelle). Les chercheur·euse·s sont au contact des différents acteurs de l’innovation (entreprises, pouvoirs publics, associations, mouvements sociaux). Le laboratoire a créé et utilise plusieurs plateformes techniques de recherche tel que le Studio Design, L’observation Lab et le Hyve dans le cadre d’un projet d’investissement Equipex CONTINUUM (développement de plate-formes de collaboration), et allié au projet PEPR ENSEMBLE (Activités collaboratives à distance - en cours de construction). L’ingénieur·e renforcera les deux équipes travaillant sur ces projets. Le laboratoire effectue des recherches sur la collaboration et la créativité dans des situations de conception, l’interaction humain/machine et la visualisation de données. Il/Elle travaillera, dans l’équipe Interact à Télécom Paris (localisation à Palaiseau) avec des chercheurs en design, psychologie et sociologie interactionnelle. https://i3.cnrs.fr/presentation/</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="recrutement"/><category term="hiring"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recrutement Ingénieur d'étude]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hiring an Assitant Associate Professor In Design</title><link href="https://samuel-huron.github.io/blog/2025/recrutement-prof-position/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hiring an Assitant Associate Professor In Design"/><published>2025-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://samuel-huron.github.io/blog/2025/recrutement-prof-position</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://samuel-huron.github.io/blog/2025/recrutement-prof-position/"><![CDATA[<p>All application for the job should be made on this website : <a href="https://institutminestelecom.recruitee.com/l/en/o/associate-professor-in-interac-design-applied-psychology-digital-technologies-permanent-contract">https://institutminestelecom.recruitee.com/l/en/o/associate-professor-in-interac-design-applied-psychology-digital-technologies-permanent-contract</a></p> <h2 id="mission">Mission</h2> <p>The open position concerns an Assistant/Associate Professor (Maitre de Conferences) that will join the INTERACT team of the Department of Economic and Social Sciences (SES) of Télécom Paris. The INTERACT team is a member of i3 laboratory (UMR CNRS 9217 - https://i3.cnrs.fr/) is one of the most prestigious research units in the field of human and social sciences applied to the study of innovation processes. It enjoys an international reputation, carries out an exceptional number of activities oriented towards the socio-economic field, notably with private companies, and is strongly committed to teaching.</p> <p>The INTERACT team conducts interdisciplinary research at the intersection of innovation, user experience, human interaction and participatory design. It explores how technologies are used and reappropriated in everyday life, drawing on user-centered approaches rooted in real-life contexts.</p> <p>Through collaboration between disciplines (ergonomic psychology, design, HMI, sociology, language sciences, engineering, etc.), the team designs more relevant interactive systems. It has a number of research platforms at its disposal: design studio, Fab Lab, VR laboratory, neurocognition, etc.</p> <p>The future recruit will contribute to advancing research on human-technology interactions.</p> <p>Your main responsibilities will be to :</p> <ul> <li>Participate in the design and implementation of courses in the fields of Interaction Design and Ergonomics, in connection with digital technologies, and contribute to the courses taught by the SES department</li> <li>Conduct research in your scientific field in connection with digital technologies, in collaboration with colleagues at the Institut Polytechnique de Paris, in particular the LTCI, Télécom Paris</li> <li>Participate in the development of partnerships, collaborations and contractual relations in your scientific field.</li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="job-requirements">Job requirements</h2> <p>To succeed in this role, you will hold a PhD and be fluent in written and spoken English.</p> <p>The successful candidate will have a solid background in the human and social sciences and/or design. He/she will be well-versed in human-technology interaction, user-centered design methods and field studies (qualitative and/or quantitative).</p> <p><strong>Expected key competencies:</strong></p> <ul> <li>Expertise in interaction design, participatory design, human and social sciences</li> <li>Ability to collaborate with researchers in computer science and social sciences</li> <li>Strong teaching, pedagogical, and supervisory skills</li> </ul> <p><strong>Additional assets:</strong></p> <ul> <li>Postdoctoral or international experience</li> <li>Proficiency in qualitative and quantitative behavior analysis tools</li> <li>Experience in developing pedagogical content</li> </ul> <p><strong>Personal qualities:</strong></p> <ul> <li>Taste for interdisciplinary teamwork</li> <li>Excellent communication, synthesis and writing skills</li> </ul> <p><strong>Why join us?</strong></p> <p>You’ll be working in a fast-growing, pleasant, green and accessible environment (particularly for people with disabilities) just 20 km from Paris. You will benefit from :</p> <p><strong>Flexible and negotiable teaching load</strong></p> <ul> <li>49 days’ annual leave (CA + RTT)</li> <li>Flexible working hours (depending on departmental and teaching activity)</li> <li>75% reimbursement of public transport season ticket</li> <li>Proximity to numerous sports facilities, concierge service, underground car park, in-house catering, etc. Staff association at school and department level</li> <li>Good to know: our social security contributions are lower than in the private sector</li> </ul> <p><strong>Selection takes place in 4 stages:</strong></p> <ul> <li>Exchange with the host team to draw up a list of shortlisted candidates</li> <li>Preliminary interview with Human Resources</li> <li>Hearing by the recruitment committee and ranking of shortlisted candidates</li> <li>Final interview with the Director of Télécom Paris</li> </ul> <p><strong>Additional information:</strong></p> <p>Application deadline: August 25, 2025 Type of contract: Permanent Contact: interact-hiring-2025@telecom-paris.fr Full job description <a href="https://partage.imt.fr/index.php/s/wpj4WTcK9ioSaGA">here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="recrutement"/><category term="hiring"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hiring a new Assistant / Associate Professor in Design]]></summary></entry></feed>